{
    "Questions": [
    {
		
                "question": "What does SQL stand for?",
                "options": [
                    "Standard Programming Language",
                    "Structured Query Language",
                    "Strong Question Language",
                    "Structured Question Language"
                ],
                "answer": "Structured Query Language"
            },
            
            {
		
              "question": "Which SQL statement is used to extract data from a database?",
              "options": [
                    "GET",
                    "SELECT",
                    "OPEN",
                    "EXTRACT"
                
                ],
                "answer": "SELECT"
            },
            
            {
		
              "question": "Which SQL statement is used to update data in a database?",
              "options": [
                    "MODIFY",
                    "SAVE AS",
                    "SAVE",
                    "UPDATE"
                
                ],
                "answer": "UPDATE"
            },
            
            {
		
              "question": "Which SQL statement is used to delete data from a database?",
              "options": [
                    "DELETE",
                    "COLLAPSE",
                    "REMOVE",
                    "TRUNCATE"
                
                ],
                "answer": "DELETE"
            },
            
            {
              "question": "Which SQL statement is used to insert new data in a database",
              "options": [
                    "ADD RECORD",
                    "INSERT INTO",
                    "ADD NEW",
                    "INSERT NEW"
                
                ],
                "answer": "INSERT INTO"
            },
            
            {
		
              "question": "With SQL, how do you select a column named 'FirstName' from a table named 'Persons'",
              "options": [
                    "EXTRACT FirstName FROM Persons",
                    "SELECT FirstName FROM Persons",
                    "SELECT Persons.FirstName",
                    "NONE OF THE ABOVE"
                
                ],
                "answer": "SELECT FirstName FROM Persons"
            },
            
            
             {
		
              "question": "With SQL, how do you select all the columns from a table named 'Persons'",
              "options": [
                    "SELECT *.Persons",
                    "SELECT Persons",
                    "SELECT [all] FROM Persons",
                    "SELECT * FROM Persons"
                
                ],
                "answer": "SELECT * FROM Persons"
            },
            
            {
		
              "question": "With SQL, how do you select all the records from a table named 'Persons' where the value of the column 'FirstName' is 'Peter'",
              "options": [
                    "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName<>'Peter'",
                    "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='Peter'",
                    "SELECT [all] FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='Peter'",
                    "SELECT [all] FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE 'Peter'"
                
                ],
                "answer": "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='Peter'"
            },
            
            {
		
              "question": "With SQL, how do you select all the records from a table named 'Persons' where the value of the column 'FirstName' starts with an 'a'",
              "options": [
                    "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='a'",
                    "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE '%a'",
                    "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE 'a%'",
                    "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='%a%'"
                
                ],
                "answer": "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName LIKE 'a%'"
            },
            
            {
		
              "question": "With SQL, how do you select all the records from a table named 'Persons' where the 'FirstName' is 'Peter' and the 'LastName' is 'Jackson'?",
              "options": [
                    "SELECT FirstName='Peter', LastName='Jackson' FROM Persons",
                    "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='Peter' AND LastName='Jackson'",
                    "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName<>'Peter' AND LastName<>'Jackson'",
                    "NONE OF THE ABOVE"
                
                ],
                "answer": "SELECT * FROM Persons WHERE FirstName='Peter' AND LastName='Jackson'"
            }
            
            
        
        
    
    ]
}
